

□ (+1) 814-777-7019 | **□** f3ixiao@gmail.com | **♠** fxiao.me | **□** xiaofen9 | **□** f-xiao

Summary _

Machine learning Researcher at Palo Alto Networks. I deisng Al/ML models to defend against cyberattacks and privacy leakages. 10+ research publications at top security conferences (BlackHat USA, IEEE S&P, USENIX SEC, etc). Interested in **systems programming** and **backend software development**.

Work Experience _____

Palo Alto Networks CA, USA

SENIOR STAFF RESEARCHER Jan. 2023 - Now

- · Fine-tune domain-specific language models (DLM) to detect text-based malware (e.g., malicious scripts).
- Design statistical models (N-Gram) to understand customer network traffic data.
- Techniques: Language Model Training, Gradient Boosting, N-Gram, Program Analysis

Google WA, USA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN

- Designed and implemented the Tsunami Callback Service, which enables Google Cloud Vulnerability Scanner to detect log4j-like vulnerabilities.
 My work is now open-sourced and actively maintained by Google https://github.com/google/tsunami-security-scanner-callback-server
- · Leveraged CI/CD techniques in Google to launch my project in production environments (early launch, exceeding expectation).
- · Gave two tech talks at Google. I shared my previous research works on web vulnerability analysis.
- · Techniques: Java, Distributed Systems, Low-latency System Design, OWASP Vulnerability Assessment, Kubernetes.

Google WA, USA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN

May. 2020 - Aug. 2020

Aug. 2017 - Sep. 2017

May. 2021 - Aug. 2021

- Made fundamental changes to the Linux virtual memory management system to enable fast I/O for Confidential VMs at Google Cloud.
- Improved Confidential VM network throughput by 20%.
- Identified a potentially serious bug in our product and received a Google Peer Bonus Award.
- Techniques: C&C++, Linux Memory Management, Linux I/O Internals, Cloud Virtualization, AMD SEV, Confidential Computing.

Tencent Shenzhen, China

• Captured and mitigate one Oday attack (CVE 2017-9805) against servers of our company.

- Found 8 high-risk vulnerabilities from the products of Tencent.
- Techniques: Python, Penetration Testing, Web Security.

Publication

5 FIRST-AUTHOR WORKS IN TOP-TIER CONFERENCES

Evaluating LLM Safety with Adversarial Decision Making Test

In Submission

Zeqing He, Huiyu Xu, Zhibo Wang, Feng Xiao

FaceObfuscator: Defending Deep Learning-based Privacy Attacks with Gradient Descent-Resistant Features in Face Recognition.

USENIX SEC'24

Shuaifan Jin, He Wang, Zhibo Wang, **Feng Xiao**, Jiahui Hu, Yuan He, Wenwen Zhang, Zhongjie Ba, Weijie Fang, Shuhong Yuan, Kui Ren

JASMINE: Scale up JavaScript Static Security Analysis with Computation-based Semantic Explanation.

IEEE S&P'24

FENG XIAO, ZHONGFU SU GUANGLIANG YANG, AND WENKE LEE

FaceObfuscator: Defending Deep Learning-based Privacy Attacks with Gradient Descent-Resistant Features in Face Recognition.

USENIX SEC'24

Shuaifan Jin, He Wang, Zhibo Wang, **Feng Xiao**, Jiahui Hu, Yuan He, Wenwen Zhang, Zhongjie Ba, Weijie Fang, Shuhong Yuan, Kui Ren

March 5, 2024 Feng Xiao · Résumé

WEBRR: A Forensic System for Replaying and Investigating Web-Based Attacks in The

USENIX SEC'24

JOEY ALLEN, ZHENG YANG, FENG XIAO, MATTHEW LANDEN, ROBERTO PERDISCI, WENKE LEE

Understanding and Mitigating Remote Code Execution Vulnerabilities in Cross-Platform Ecosystem.

ACM CCS'22

FENG XIAO, IAN ZHENG, JOEY ALLEN, GUANGLIANG YANG, AND WENKE LEE

Abusing Hidden Properties to Attack Node.js Ecosystem.

USENIX Security'21

FENG XIAO, JIANWEI HUANG, YICHANG XIONG, GUANGLIANG YANG, HONG HU, GUOFEI GU, AND WENKE LEE

Discovering Hidden Properties to Attack Node.js Ecosystem.

BlackHat'20

FENG XIAO, JIANWEI HUANG, YICHANG XIONG, GUANGLIANG YANG, HONG HU, GUOFEI GU, AND WENKE LEE

Unexpected Data Dependency Creation and Chaining: A New Attack to SDN.

IEEE S&P'20

FENG XIAO, JINQUAN ZHANG, JIANWEI HUANG, GUOFEI GU, DINGHAO WU, PENG LIU

PatternListener: Cracking Android Pattern Lock Using Acoustic Signals.

ACM CCS'18

Man Zhou, Qian Wang, Jingxiao Yang, Qi Li, Feng Xiao, Zhibo Wang, Xiaofeng Chen.

Hacking the Brain: Customize Evil Protocol to Pwn an SDN Controller.

DEFCON'18

FENG XIAO, JIANWEI HUANG, PENG LIU.

Enabling Secure Location Authentication in Drone (poster).

ACM MobiCom'17

FENG XIAO, MAN ZHOU, YOUCHENG LIYE, JINGXIAO YANG, QIAN WANG.

Education

Georgia Institute of Technology

Atlanta, USA

Ph.D. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Jul. 2019 - Dec. 2023

- · Working on system security with Prof. Wenke Lee.
- GPA: 3.9/4

Wuhan University

Wuhan, China

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE Sept. 2014 - Jun. 2018

• GPA: 3.87/4

Honors_

2021	Most Innovative Research Runner-up	Pwnie Award, USA
2019	Chair Fellowship.	Atlanta, USA
2018	Rednor IST Fellowship.	State College, USA
2018	ACM CCS Student Travel Grant Award.	Toronto, Canada
2017	LeiJun Scholarship (Top 1 out of 310).	Wuhan, China
2016	National Scholarship (Awarded to top 0.2% undergrads nationwide)	Wuhan, China
2015	Yuanyi Scholarship.	Wuhan, China

Programming languages _____

Natively fluent: C, Java, Python, Node.js

Conversationally fluent: C++, PHP, Matlab